<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Life-Related on Rathtakrit</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/life-related/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life-Related on Rathtakrit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:35:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/life-related/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>To all the Jacks, and all the trade you persuade</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/to-all-the-jacks-and-all-the-trade-you-persuade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:35:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/to-all-the-jacks-and-all-the-trade-you-persuade/</guid>
      <description>For those people who do a bunch of things, but not any in particular</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The only way to do great work is to love what you do.”</p>
<p>— Steve Jobs</p></blockquote>
<h2 id="jacks-of-all-trades">Jacks of all Trades</h2>
<p>&ldquo;Jack of all trades,&rdquo; a saying that would best describe myself. I&rsquo;m good with a lot of things, but nothing <em>great</em> in particular. I have a shit load of hobbies I like to do (photography, music, writing, reading, movies and more) but if someone were to ask what I do the best, I wouldn&rsquo;t be able to give an answer</p>
<p>This does not only cover my hobbies thought, it covers everything. In academia, I couldn&rsquo;t pinpoint which subject I like the most (except biology, I hate biology), and no, I&rsquo;m not that super smart kid in class who good in every topics. Vise-versa, I&rsquo;m bad at every topic! equally bad in all of them!</p>
<p>In High-school, the thing I do best is extra-curricular. With my wide range of skills, I believe that the best use of this skills is in <strong>Management position</strong> and I did just that, somehow, maybe cuz we&rsquo;re living in a simulation, I was a student president! And I really have fun conducting meetings, helping other people and commenting on peoples&rsquo; work.</p>
<h2 id="master-of-none">Master of None</h2>
<p>But life is funny, and in this era of excess. We need to be truly <strong>GREAT</strong> in something to standout. In my final year of high school, and the very same problematic choice every teenager have to face. the very question that will determine what you do for the rest of your life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What will you study?</p></blockquote>
<p>The answer varies from person to person, and some may have a clear answer for it. I have thought about this question for a really long time, and before my time in high school. My answer would always be &lsquo;&lsquo;computer engineer&rsquo;&rsquo; because I love technology. and I have a little background in programming. However, things changed. I know that I like management, I&rsquo;m quite okay with it also(not bragging),  I also  really like weird abstract concept: Psychology, Philosophy, and arts? which make me started to think.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Is there more path I can pursue?</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="the-decision">The Decision</h3>
<p>After multiple talks with my counselors. I finally decide, I would become an <em><strong>Industrial Engineer</strong></em>, An engineer whom study in multiple of fields. wide range of topics, can work in multiple industry. Since I have no specific subject I love, and I like management, this should be the correct path&hellip;&hellip;right?</p>
<p>1 year in university have passed,
and all I wanted to study is computing.</p>
<p>While the first year mostly filled with introductory course, I found myself to be highly interest in computing-related subjects. I found myself doing work our side of my own class.</p>
<p>Even as far as to apply for a transfer into department of computing.</p>
<h3 id="is-there-a-place-for-jacks-in-today-society">Is there a place for Jacks in today society?</h3>
<p>There are mainly 3 reasons I change my mind yet again.</p>
<ol>
<li>I like tech</li>
<li>To survive and shine in today society, you have to be truly talented at <em>something</em></li>
<li>A manager is good at everything, but he must be great at <em>something</em>
I needed that <em>something</em>, a specific talent I could tell people I do. Not a 5 second pause thinking in my own mind &ldquo;Ahh, shit I don&rsquo;t know I do a lot of things.&rdquo; I believe IE is a great career, but I also believe that maybe, there is no place for us Jacks in this world&hellip;&hellip;&hellip;&hellip;&hellip;.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>But I got rejected</strong></p>
<h2 id="though-oftentimes">Though oftentimes</h2>
<h2 id="better-than-master-of-one">Better than master of one</h2>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Jack of all trades master of none, though oftentimes better than master of one</strong>
—William Shakespear</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
