<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Life-Related on Rathtakrit</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/life-related/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life-Related on Rathtakrit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:35:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/life-related/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>To all the Jacks, and all the trade you persuade</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/to-all-the-jacks-and-all-the-trade-you-persuade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:35:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/to-all-the-jacks-and-all-the-trade-you-persuade/</guid>
      <description>For those people who do a bunch of things, but not any in particular</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The only way to do great work is to love what you do.”</p>
<p>— Steve Jobs</p></blockquote>
<h2 id="jacks-of-all-trades">Jacks of all Trades</h2>
<p>&ldquo;Jack of all trades&rdquo; is a saying that would best describe myself. I&rsquo;m good with a lot of things, but nothing <em>great</em> in particular. I have a shit load of hobbies I like to do (photography, music, writing, reading, movies and more) but if someone were to ask what I do the best, I wouldn&rsquo;t be able to give an answer</p>
<p>This does not only cover my hobbies thought, it covers everything. In academia, I couldn&rsquo;t pinpoint which subject I like the most (except biology, I hate biology), and no, I&rsquo;m not that super smart kid in class who good in every topics. Vise-versa, I&rsquo;m bad at every topic! equally bad in all of them!</p>
<p>In High-school, the thing I do best is extra-curricular. With my wide range of skills, I believe that the best use of this skills is in <strong>Management position</strong> and I did just that, somehow, maybe cuz we&rsquo;re living in a simulation. I was a student president! and I really have fun conducting meetings, helping other people and commenting on peoples&rsquo; work.</p>
<h2 id="master-of-none">Master of None</h2>
<p>But life is funny, and in this era of excess. We need to be truly <strong>GREAT</strong> in something to standout. In my final year of High school, and the very same problematic choice every teenager have to face. the very question that will determine what you do for the rest of your life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What will you study?</p></blockquote>
<p>The answer varies from person to person, and some may have a clear answer for it. I have thought about this question for a really long time, and before becoming student president. My answer would always be &lsquo;&lsquo;computer engineer&rsquo;&rsquo; because I love technology. and I have a little background in programming.
But, after becoming a student president. I also know that I like management, I&rsquo;m quite good with it also(not bragging, I think I&rsquo;m quite okay with it alrighty). and I really like weird abstract concept: Psychology, Philosophy, and arts? I co</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
