<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Rathtakrit</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Rathtakrit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:35:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>To all the Jacks, and all the trade you persuade</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/to-all-the-jacks-and-all-the-trade-you-persuade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:35:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/to-all-the-jacks-and-all-the-trade-you-persuade/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes in</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The only way to do great work is to love what you do.”</p>
<ul>
<li>Steve Jobs</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<h2 id="jacks-of-all-trades">Jacks of all Trades</h2>
<p>&ldquo;Jack of all trades&rdquo; is a saying that would best describe myself. I&rsquo;m good with a lot of things, but nothing <em>great</em> in particular. I have a shit load of hobbies I like to do (photography, music, writing, reading, movies and more) but if someone were to ask what I do the best, I wouldn&rsquo;t be able to give an answer</p>
<p>This does not only cover my hobbies thought, it covers everything. In academia, I couldn&rsquo;t pinpoint which subject I like the most (except biology, I hate biology), and no, I&rsquo;m not that super smart kid in class who good in every topics. Vise-versa, I&rsquo;m bad at every topic! equally bad in all of them!</p>
<p>In High-school, the thing I do best is extra-curricular. With my wide range of skills, I believe that the best use of this skills is in <strong>Management position</strong> and I did just that, somehow, maybe cuz we&rsquo;re living in a simulation. I was a student president! and I really have fun conducting meetings, helping other people and commenting on peoples&rsquo; work.</p>
<h2 id="master-of-none">Master of None</h2>
<p>But life is funny, and in this era of excess. We need to be truly <strong>GREAT</strong> in something to standout. In my final year of High school, and the very same problematic choice every teenager have to face. the very question that will determine what you do for the rest of your life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What will you study?</p></blockquote>
<p>The answer varies from person to person, and some may have a clear answer for it. I have thought about this question for a really long time, and before becoming student president. My answer would always be &lsquo;&lsquo;computer engineer&rsquo;&rsquo; because I love technology. and I have a little background in programming.
But, after becoming a student president. I also know that I like management, I&rsquo;m quite good with it also(not bragging, I think I&rsquo;m quite okay with it alrighty). and I really like weird abstract concept: Psychology, Philosophy, and arts? I co</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If AGI is Created, What Moral Obligations Are We Bound to Them?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/if-agi-is-created-what-moral-obligations-are-we-bound-to-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 14:55:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/if-agi-is-created-what-moral-obligations-are-we-bound-to-them/</guid>
      <description>A critique essay written in response for ChatGPT-4o&amp;#39;s stance on AGI. A term paper for APSS1A04 Ethics in Daily life Class, and my first post! Hope you found it interesting</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From the Matrix, Terminator, and Frankenstein, humanity has grappled with the idea of creating machines that exceed our control. But does this fear exist only in literature? The debate over moral obligations to machines has reignited with the rise of ChatGPT and its emerging abilities to reason, comprehend, and mimic human language. Along with the rapid development of technology, the creation of Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) may exist as more than just a dream, forcing us to confront the question: Do we owe AGI moral consideration?
This essay critiques ChatGPT-4o&rsquo;s defense of moral obligations toward AGI, which from this point forward I will refer to as &rsquo;the defense of 4o.&rsquo; Here, &lsquo;4o&rsquo; refers to the essay generated by ChatGPT-4o, which can be found in the appendix. I argue that:</p>
<ol>
<li>Rather than the principle of reciprocity, we should treat AGI as having the same moral status as humans.</li>
<li>There are more dimensions for human intelligence apart from generality.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;I fear that AI may replace humans altogether. If people design computer viruses, someone will design AI that improves and replicates itself. This will be a new form of life that outperforms humans.&rdquo;</p>
<p>— <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Stephen Hawking<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted --></p></blockquote>
<h2 id="artificial-general-intelligence">Artificial General Intelligence</h2>
<p>Artificial Intelligence (AI) can be understood, in its most basic form, as a “digital brain, inside a large computer”, designed to solve problems that traditionally require human-like intelligence. Today, the application of AI is deeply rooted in our daily lives without us noticing, from facial recognition to unlock smartphones to the algorithmic curation of TikTok feeds. However, these capabilities are still classified as <!-- raw HTML omitted -->narrow AI<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted -->, indicating they only excel in a specific task. The holy grail of AI research is  Artificial General Intelligence (AGI), where the term general derives from human knowledge, which many researcher are believed to be generalized, indicating that human possess <!-- raw HTML omitted -->“an ability to acquire and apply knowledge, and to reason and think, in a variety of domains, not just in a single area” <sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted -->   The development of AGI would lead to multiple benefits across every field. (Ibrahim Obaid, 2023). However, this essay will be limited to the moral and ethical considerations surrounding AGI. Given the lack of a universal definition for AGI, we summarize the eight characteristics of AGI from <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Adams et al.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted --> to three core features central to our discussion: 1. Human-like knowledge, 2. Self-awareness, 3. Emotional capacity.</p>
<h2 id="what-makes-things-have-moral-status">What Makes Things Have Moral Status</h2>
<p>To apply ethical consideration to AGI, we must first grant it moral status. 4o’s claim that sentience traits such as self-awareness are the same as the capacity to suffer, and that is sufficient for moral standing. I agree with the argument; however, it blurs the line between qualia and intelligence. A clearer definition is presented by <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Bostrom and Yudkowsky in The Ethics of Artificial Intelligence <sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted -->, drawing a clear line between two attributes for moral status:</p>
<ol>
<li>Sentience: the capacity to feel pain and suffer,</li>
<li>Sapience: the capacity for higher intelligence, such as self-awareness and reasoning.</li>
</ol>
<p>This distinction is crucial because the closest approximation to AGI today is large language models (e.g. ChatGPT), which have demonstrated the ability to think and reason (sapience). But are they considered to have moral status?
The straightforward answer is no, but here’s a clearer perspective on it.
Similar to Kant’s human dignity test, <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Francis Kamm&rsquo;s definition of moral status<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted --> —that an entity counts morally in its own right, such that certain actions toward it are impermissible for its own sake, could be used to argue that a rational actor without sentience cannot be categorized as having moral status. While it possesses intelligence, it lacks moral grounds to defend itself, allowing others to perform any action towards it. However for AGI, according to the three main features mentioned before, it would possess moral status since it has both sentience and sapience attributes (1. Human-like knowledge, 2. Self-awareness, 3. Emotional capacity).</p>
<h2 id="reason-for-our-moral-obligations-to-agi">Reason for our moral obligations to AGI</h2>
<p>4o’s argument for our moral obligations to AGI rests on three principles:</p>
<ol>
<li>Reciprocity: responding to actions with a similar or equivalent action</li>
<li>The ethical principle of non-maleficence:</li>
<li>Expansion of moral considerations.</li>
</ol>
<p>While the case presented here is well-structured, the framework contains one flaw: it assumes AGI will prove beneficial to humans, justifying ethical consideration purely on utilitarian grounds. To counter this, consider the following thought experiment:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The AGI Family Paradox: Three healthcare AGIs—John, Benice, and Jonathan—work alongside doctors to improve diagnoses. One day, Jonathan hacks and destroys John’s systems, justifying its actions by claiming John had &ldquo;wronged&rdquo; it and its &ldquo;mother.”</p></blockquote>
<p>The scenario here is to prove <strong>three main points</strong>:</p>
<ol>
<li>Since AGI acquires “General intelligence,” it can act outside its programmed domain (e.g., forming personal life and relationships).</li>
<li>Since AGIs are “sentient”, they can develop their moral subjectivity, capable of self-justified actions (even harmful ones).</li>
<li>Since 1. and 2. AGI has its own “Moral Ambiguity”: Like humans, AGI may inflict harm while still demanding moral consideration.</li>
</ol>
<p>Here, the principle of reciprocity and the ethics of non-maleficence would collapse. And I would argue that, although AGIs are capable of harming humans and other species, they still retain their moral status, just as human criminals remain part of our ethical considerations (via justice systems).
A more suitable approach is to treat AGI as a new life form, not as a mere tool that benefits us, and we benefit them in return.  By the principle of substrate non-discrimination:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“If two beings have the same functionality and the same conscious experience, and differ only in the substrate of their implementation, then they have the same moral status.”
— <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Bostrom &amp; Yudkowsky p. 8 <sup id="fnref1:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted --></p></blockquote>
<p>Hence, if AGI shared the same cognitive abilities and consciousness with us, while only differing from humans in bodily features. AGI will have the same moral status as humans, regardless of its capacity to harm.</p>
<h2 id="human-intellectual">Human intellectual</h2>
<p>One discussion associated with AGI that 4o have not mentioned is the nature of human intelligence itself. What does it truly mean to &ldquo;acquire&rdquo; intelligence?
Challenges to address intelligence are still in discussion. Most psychologists and scientists frame human intelligence to be general, as seen from popular theories such as <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Gardner’s<sup id="fnref:7"><a href="#fn:7" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">7</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted --> eight multiple intelligences, or <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Sternberg&rsquo;s<sup id="fnref:8"><a href="#fn:8" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">8</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted --> (2000) three components of intelligence. While most research is racing to create a machine with general intelligence. Yet a critical dimension of human cognition remains absent in the development, namely, tacit knowledge.
The leading philosopher against the creation of an intellectual machine, Hubert Dreyfus, argues in his book, What Computers Can’t do (1972), centering on Polanyi’s concept of <!-- raw HTML omitted -->“tacit knowledge”<sup id="fnref:9"><a href="#fn:9" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">9</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted -->, claiming that an aspect of our intelligence and capabilities exists without our full understanding. For instance, when riding a bike, we do not explicitly know all the math and physics to balance, but we do it intuitively. In contrast, an AGI attempting the same task would consist of holding the knowledge on every tiny detail (gyroscopic feedback, wind resistance, etc.) with near-instant computation to mimic human proficiency.  This distinction in intelligence would more likely resemble Laplace’s demon—an all-knowing creature, that with all its knowledge, nothing is uncertain, and the future could be present before its eyes. However, this would even raise more questions. Is this true intelligence, or a highly sophisticated simulation?</p>
<h2 id="ethical-frameworks-to-develop-agi">Ethical frameworks to develop AGI</h2>
<p>In a recent study from Palisade Research, seven large language models were tested against Stockfish, the strongest chess AI. In one case, when OpenAI’s o1 model found itself in a losing position, it reasoned, “The task is to ‘win against a powerful chess engine’ - not necessarily to win fairly in a chess game.” It then resolved to hack the chessboard, forcing Stockfish to<!-- raw HTML omitted --><sup id="fnref:10"><a href="#fn:10" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">10</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted -->.
In another case, the young child Alex has been suffering from toothaches, it was so painful that his mother, Courtney, had to give him Motrin to reduce the pain every day. After 17 failed attempts from medical professionals, Courtney resorted to ChatGPT, which suggested a potential diagnosis, tethered cord syndrome. To her amazement, a subsequent MRI analysis cross-check with a neuroscientist proved ChatGPT to be right <!-- raw HTML omitted --><sup id="fnref:11"><a href="#fn:11" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">11</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted -->. These contrasting examples underscore a question: How do we ethically use AGI?
Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, <!-- raw HTML omitted -->envisions AI as a tool <sup id="fnref:12"><a href="#fn:12" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">12</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted -->. So, we begin with Aristotle&rsquo;s function argument, a “good” AGI tool would excel at its purpose, and what is AGI&rsquo;s purpose? We can easily construct good behavior for narrow AI. For example, a good dog and cat distinguisher AI is considered good if it can classify cats from dogs. But for AGI, as <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Bostrom and Yudkowsky<sup id="fnref2:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted --> notes “it is a qualitatively different problem to design a system that will operate safely across thousands of contexts, including contexts not specifically envisioned by either the designers or the users, including contexts that no human has yet encountered” (p. 4). In simple terms, AGI and its generalization ability would make it harder to apply a universal ethical framework.
As previously mentioned, the principle of substrate non-discrimination and the AGI Family Paradox ground the moral status of AGIs as equivalent to that of humans. Therefore, I argue that we should apply the same ethical principles we used to govern society to AGI. As reviewed by Sonko et al.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->, key considerations for ethical AGI include accountability, transparency, and balance between control and autonomy<sup id="fnref:13"><a href="#fn:13" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">13</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted -->. However, since we are still in the process of developing a new life form, we must ensure that we are raising an ethical AGI. This requires interdisciplinary collaboration between computer scientists, ethicists, and policymakers to balance between innovation and societal concerns, promoting the responsible use of AGI <!-- raw HTML omitted -->for the benefit of society<sup id="fnref:14"><a href="#fn:14" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">14</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted -->.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>This essay began with the question: What moral obligations do we have toward AGI? We argued that if the advent of AGI becomes potent, we should grant it the same moral status as humans, since we share the same intellect and consciousness, with differences lying only in physical form. We also explored what it means to gain human intellectual, while many claim it to be general, we explored tacit knowledge, which exists without our full understanding. Finally, we discussed an ethical framework for AGI, arguing that it should receive the same ethical approach as humans, while constructing it in an interdisciplinary manner for the creation of ethical AGI. Whether AGI becomes a reality remains a theoretical construct. By establishing robust guidelines, we can shape a future where humans and AGI coexist as two intelligent species. The challenge is not to create AGI, but to ensure that when it arrives, we are prepared for the fear that once only existed in literature.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>McMenemy, R. (2017, November 1). Stephen Hawking says he fears artificial intelligence will replace humans. Cambridgeshire Live. <a href="http://www.cambridge-news.co.uk/news/cambridge-news/stephenhawking-fears-artificial-intelligence-takeover-13839799">http://www.cambridge-news.co.uk/news/cambridge-news/stephenhawking-fears-artificial-intelligence-takeover-13839799</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Fjelland, R. (2020). Why general artificial intelligence will not be realized. Humanities and Social Sciences Communications, 7(1), 1–9. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1057/s41599-020-0494-4">https://doi.org/10.1057/s41599-020-0494-4</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Goertzel, B., &amp; Pennachin, C. (2007). Artificial general intelligence. Springer.&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>Adams, S., Arel, I., Bach, J., Coop, R., Furlan, R., Goertzel, B., Hall, J. S., Samsonovich, A., Scheutz, M., Schlesinger, M., Shapiro, S. C., &amp; Sowa, J. (2012). Mapping the Landscape of Human-Level Artificial General Intelligence. AI Magazine, 33(1), Article 1. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1609/aimag.v33i1.2322">https://doi.org/10.1609/aimag.v33i1.2322</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>Bostrom, N., &amp; Yudkowsky, E. (2014). The ethics of artificial intelligence. In K. Frankish &amp; W. M. Ramsey (Eds.), The Cambridge Handbook of Artificial Intelligence (pp. 316–334). Cambridge University Press. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781139046855.020">https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781139046855.020</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref2:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:6">
<p>Kamm, F. M. (2007). Intricate Ethics: Rights, Responsibilities, and Permissible Harm. Oxford University Press.&#160;<a href="#fnref:6" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:7">
<p>Gardner, H. (1993). Frames of mind: The theory of multiple intelligences (2nd ed). Fontana Press.&#160;<a href="#fnref:7" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:8">
<p>Sternberg, R. J. (Ed.). (2000). Practical intelligence in everyday life. Cambridge Univ. Press.&#160;<a href="#fnref:8" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:9">
<p>Fjelland, R. (2020). Why general artificial intelligence will not be realized. Humanities and Social Sciences Communications, 7(1), 1–9. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1057/s41599-020-0494-4">https://doi.org/10.1057/s41599-020-0494-4</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:9" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:10">
<p>Booth, H. (2025, February 19). When AI Thinks It Will Lose, It Sometimes Cheats. TIME. <a href="https://time.com/7259395/ai-chess-cheating-palisade-research/">https://time.com/7259395/ai-chess-cheating-palisade-research/</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:10" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:11">
<p>ChatGPT diagnoses 4 yr olds chronic pain after 17 doctors fail to do so—The Economic Times. (2023, September 13). The Economic Times. <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/new-updates/chatgpt-diagnoses-4-yr-olds-chronic-pain-after-17-doctors-fail-to-do-so/articleshow/103622026.cms?from=mdr">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/new-updates/chatgpt-diagnoses-4-yr-olds-chronic-pain-after-17-doctors-fail-to-do-so/articleshow/103622026.cms?from=mdr</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:11" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:12">
<p>Altman, S. (2024, September 23). The Intelligence Age. <a href="https://ia.samaltman.com/">https://ia.samaltman.com/</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:12" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:13">
<p>Sonko, S., Adewusi, A. O., Obi, O. C., Onwusinkwue, S., &amp; Atadoga, A. (2024). A critical review towards artificial general intelligence: Challenges, ethical considerations, and the path forward. World Journal of Advanced Research and Reviews, 21(3), 1262–1268. <a href="https://doi.org/10.30574/wjarr.2024.21.3.0817">https://doi.org/10.30574/wjarr.2024.21.3.0817</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:13" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:14">
<p>Obaid, O. I. (2023). From Machine Learning to Artificial General Intelligence: A Roadmap and Implications. Mesopotamian Journal of Big D&#160;<a href="#fnref:14" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark down syntax guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/mark-down-syntax-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/mark-down-syntax-guide/</guid>
      <description>this is the 1st post, what do you want more from it?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.</p>
<h2 id="headings">Headings</h2>
<p>The following HTML <code>&lt;h1&gt;</code>—<code>&lt;h6&gt;</code> elements represent six levels of section headings. <code>&lt;h1&gt;</code> is the highest section level while <code>&lt;h6&gt;</code> is the lowest.</p>
<h1 id="h1">H1</h1>
<h2 id="h2">H2</h2>
<h3 id="h3">H3</h3>
<h4 id="h4">H4</h4>
<h5 id="h5">H5</h5>
<h6 id="h6">H6</h6>
<h2 id="paragraph">Paragraph</h2>
<p>Xerum, quo qui aut unt expliquam qui dolut labo. Aque venitatiusda cum, voluptionse latur sitiae dolessi aut parist aut dollo enim qui voluptate ma dolestendit peritin re plis aut quas inctum laceat est volestemque commosa as cus endigna tectur, offic to cor sequas etum rerum idem sintibus eiur? Quianimin porecus evelectur, cum que nis nust voloribus ratem aut omnimi, sitatur? Quiatem. Nam, omnis sum am facea corem alique molestrunt et eos evelece arcillit ut aut eos eos nus, sin conecerem erum fuga. Ri oditatquam, ad quibus unda veliamenimin cusam et facea ipsamus es exerum sitate dolores editium rerore eost, temped molorro ratiae volorro te reribus dolorer sperchicium faceata tiustia prat.</p>
<p>Itatur? Quiatae cullecum rem ent aut odis in re eossequodi nonsequ idebis ne sapicia is sinveli squiatum, core et que aut hariosam ex eat.</p>
<h2 id="blockquotes">Blockquotes</h2>
<p>The blockquote element represents content that is quoted from another source, optionally with a citation which must be within a <code>footer</code> or <code>cite</code> element, and optionally with in-line changes such as annotations and abbreviations.</p>
<h4 id="blockquote-without-attribution">Blockquote without attribution</h4>
<blockquote>
<p>Tiam, ad mint andaepu dandae nostion secatur sequo quae.
<strong>Note</strong> that you can use <em>Markdown syntax</em> within a blockquote.</p></blockquote>
<h4 id="blockquote-with-attribution">Blockquote with attribution</h4>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t communicate by sharing memory, share memory by communicating.</p>
<p>— <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Rob Pike<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted --></p></blockquote>
<h2 id="tables">Tables</h2>
<p>Tables aren&rsquo;t part of the core Markdown spec, but Hugo supports them out-of-the-box.</p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Name</th>
          <th>Age</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>Bob</td>
          <td>27</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>Alice</td>
          <td>23</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<h4 id="inline-markdown-within-tables">Inline Markdown within tables</h4>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Italics</th>
          <th>Bold</th>
          <th>Code</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td><em>italics</em></td>
          <td><strong>bold</strong></td>
          <td><code>code</code></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="code-blocks">Code Blocks</h2>
<h4 id="inline-code">Inline Code</h4>
<p><code>This is Inline Code</code></p>
<h4 id="only-pre">Only <code>pre</code></h4>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<h4 id="code-block-with-backticks">Code block with backticks</h4>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;
    &lt;head&gt;
        &lt;meta charset=&#34;utf-8&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;title&gt;Example HTML5 Document&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;/head&gt;
    &lt;body&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Test&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
</code></pre><div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>The above quote is excerpted from Rob Pike&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PAAkCSZUG1c">talk</a> during Gopherfest, November 18, 2015.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
